<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Running for Refugees</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/runningforrefugees//</link>
    <atom:link href="/runningforrefugees//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 12:59:18 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 12:59:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am Running for Refugees</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like a challenge. This summer, I’ll be running 32 marathons in 36 days, covering the 950 miles from the very bottom to the very top of the UK. I’ve never actually run further than 13 miles in a go, so the prospect of pegging it all the way from Land’s End to John O’Groats on foot is more than a little terrifying.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Why am I doing this? That’s the easy bit. I want to raise money and awareness for the amazing work of The Refugee Council. We’ve all heard a lot this past year about the on-going refugee crisis. It is, in terms of the number of people, the largest refugee crisis since WWII. It can be hard, however, to appreciate the individual stories behind these headline statistics and it’s on this individual level that the work of The Refugee Council makes such a difference. For those that have made the treacherous journey just to escape violence and persecution at home, The Refugee Council lends a helping a hand and supports them and their families to start a new life.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Aside from training, I’ll spend the time between now and when I do the run in September learning about the work of The Refugee Council, understanding what they do and how it makes a difference. I’ll share what I’ve learned both on this blog and via my YouTube channel.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Follow this blog, share the project with people you know, become a host location en-route - any support is massively appreciated. You can also directly support our fundraising efforts by donating here. Thank you!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Matt G.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 10:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/runningforrefugees//2016/03/05/I-am-Running-for-Refugees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/runningforrefugees//2016/03/05/I-am-Running-for-Refugees.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
