<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Running for Refugees</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 21:47:51 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 21:47:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Final Countdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since my last blog and suddenly I find myself just over two weeks away from starting this mammoth challenge. Before looking ahead though I’d like to recap what’s happened since I last wrote.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First of all the pub quiz! On 3rd August we packed 90ish people into an upstairs room in The Rose pub Vauxhall. There literally wasn’t a chair left spare and so I found myself perching on a radiator at the front of the room! For three hours the teams were treated to a brilliant quiz that had had been lovingly created by Jess and Sian, two of friends from my time at Comic Relief. Thank you to everyone that attended and especially to quiz masters Jess and Sian; we raised a fantastic £700. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A few days later it was time for fundraising event number two. But rather than being in another part of London or the UK, this fundraiser took place in Melbourne, Australia. My good friends Jo and Liv organised a film screening at a Melbourne cinema and raised $300. I have even heard that the film wasn’t great (one viewer jokingly asked for a refund). Nonetheless I really appreciate the support of the cause from the other side of the world. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have said this before and will undoubtedly say it again but the kindness of others has been the best part of this journey so far. Whether they’re good friends or relative strangers, people have been so generous with their words, their time and indeed with their money. Thank you to you all. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So now to dare to look forward. There are 14 sleeps until I take my first steps at Land’s End on 3rd September. In that time I will finish my job, move out of London and attempt to get as much of my university work done as possible. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With all that in mind, I am understandably fairly nervous. However the dominant feeling is excitement; I really can’t wait to get started. I look forward to having you along for the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/08/20/Final-Countdown.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/08/20/Final-Countdown.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marathon number one</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a couple of weeks since my last blog post and boy has a lot happened. To avoid getting side-tracked by politics, let’s start with the main running news: I have completed a marathon! That’s right, I have now officially completed the 26.3 mile distance. It is another huge milestone for me and has further bolstered my confidence that I can actually do this thing.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I completed the marathon last Sunday morning, running from my flat in Ealing to various central London landmarks and back again. Perhaps most pleasingly my body wasn’t too angry with me afterwards. Sure there were a few aches but structurally things seem to be mostly OK! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The next phase of training focuses on doing these long distances with increasing frequency. Training has so far been structured around 6 runs in a week; 3 short distance, 2 medium distance and 1 long distance. Now I will start to move towards slightly shorter long distance runs but completing them on all 6 days. For example next week I will be running 17.5 miles each day. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not only is this a different physical challenge but it is an entirely different mental challenge. I have become used to psyching myself up for the longest run of the week and being comforted by the knowledge of a short run the next day. I will need to change how I think about each run and put in place methods to avoid tedium. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Before signing off, I would like to draw your attention to a quiz night taking in place in Vauxhall London on 3rd August. It will be a chance to raise some more money for the refugee council and to generally have a good time! Full details can be found on the Facebook page. Everyone is welcome – three words that will take me back to my political ponderings!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/07/04/Marathon-number-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/07/04/Marathon-number-one.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>London</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love London. I love living here, I love working here and I love running here too. Each run can be almost completely different and I enjoy getting lost in areas of the city that I haven’t fully explored.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Just as enjoyable however, is the challenge of connecting up the pockets of the city that I do know. A prime example was my run this Sunday. I exited Green Park tube at 07:00am and set off in the direction of Leicester Square. From there I made my way down the Strand and eventually to the Tower of London, before tracing part of the London Marathon route from Tower Bridge to Canary Wharf. I hugged the Thames as it flows around the Docklands and with a few twists and turns, emerged near Canning Town station.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Heading north I followed the tracks of the jubilee line to Stratford and excitedly entered the Queen Elizabeth Olympic Park. It’s hard to believe that it is almost four years ago that I was lucky enough to work there for that incredible summer. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There was enough time for a quick circuit of Hackney Marshes before winding my way through Hackney Wick to Victoria Park. The final leg took me down the Regents Canal to finish back in Canary Wharf. Incidentally Canary Wharf also holds brilliant memories for me of my year of work on the Olympic &amp;amp; Paralympic Games. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Overall the run allowed me to stitch several areas of this great city together. What’s exciting for me is that I will always have new places to find and as an extension always have yet more opportunities to weave nostalgia with exploration. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As a complete aside point, I would like to give a quick mention to the elderly lady who beamed at me as I was going past Star Lane DLR on Sunday. The chance of you ever reading this is almost zero but if you ever do, please know that your smile and the way you mimed running along with me, was exactly the boost I needed at that point of the run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/06/13/London.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/06/13/London.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Rude Awakening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally breaking the 20 mile mark has brought with it mixed feelings.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Let’s start with the positives. Both physiologically and psychologically it represents a big milestone. Before I began training, the furthest I had run was a half marathon and I remember seeing that 13 mile distance as psychologically difficult to go past. So to have reached 20 miles gives me confidence that I’m going in the right direction!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I did however find the run very difficult to complete. So far my training has progressed without each increase in distance feeling too scary or physically unattainable. Sure I have had injuries and struggled with fitting in all my training  but once I have got out and onto the road I have felt able to complete each run. The 20 miler didn’t feel like that! I had to stop to stretch at 15 miles and my legs felt like lead by the time I dragged myself to the end. It has been a rude awakening to the work I have left to do, not only to run 6 miles further but to do that 33 times.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are some lessons to be learnt too. It was a pretty hot and muggy day but naively I chose to forgo the water to reduce weight/ inconvenience.  My lips getting stuck together by the 11th mile perhaps indicates that my lack of hydration did play its part in my rapid performance decline towards the end of the run.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Above all else, my top tip from this ‘journey’ so far is to remain as positive as possible. After all, I always knew that this experience was going to be a challenge; it would be disappointing if it wasn’t!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/06/07/A-Rude-Awakening.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/06/07/A-Rude-Awakening.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An additional challenge?!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenge of running 33ish marathons in 37 days, I hope you will agree, is suitably challenging. Earlier this week I was talking to a friend about the run when she asked for clarification about exactly what was involved. She had thought that the challenge not only included the marathons but that I was going to attempt it without sleep. ‘5 weeks without sleep!?’ I said, ‘whilst running a marathon each day?’. She replied, ‘well I was a bit worried!’.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the interests of openness I would like to take this opportunity to confirm that I intend to be sleeping a lot during the challenge. But thank you Gemma for thinking about my well being, it’s genuinely very kind of you. Thank you for making me laugh too!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In other news, I am excited to say that I will be making my first radio appearance next week. Next Tuesday morning I will be speaking about the run on the Star Radios breakfast show in Cambridge. You can listen on the web here.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That’s all lovely people. Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/05/28/An-additional-challenge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/05/28/An-additional-challenge.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Injuries</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Injuries are a worry for any runner, especially when you are deep into training. And of course injuries come in all shapes and sizes and as a result of many different root causes. As I started training in earnest late last year, I increased my mileage too quickly and picked up a knee injury as a result. A period of frustrating inactivity followed. To protect my knees, I  decided to adjust my running style but with changes in style comes knock on effects on other areas of the body. In this case it was my foot that suffered and another period of frustrating inactivity followed. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That was back in February and up until a week ago I had enjoyed a fantastic stretch of injury free bliss! I am pleased to report that my latest injury is a minor one however its cause has meant that it is no less frustrating than my previous mishaps. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In a nutshell I fell over. I was running home during the beautiful spell of hot weather that we recently enjoyed and turned into a small south London park full with people enjoying the sun. In order to cut the corner and head across the park I made the decision to jump over a shin high railing (it was more of a hop). But something went wrong; my hop wasn’t high enough and my leading foot caught the railing bringing me crashing down onto my left knee.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The cut that resulted was pretty deep and understandably my body reacted with a king sized bruise. It’s important to learn lessons in life and in this case it is to jump rather than hop!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/05/18/Injuries.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/05/18/Injuries.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is it too early to say thank you?!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started to properly think about this challenge back in the middle of 2015, I quickly realised that I was going to need a fair bit of help. Who would travel with me, how would these people travel, where would we stay, who could I ask to help with editing videos etc. etc. I needn’t have worried. People have been so incredibly generous and very willing to give their time, expertise or indeed money to the challenge.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It all started with a core group of close friends and family who very kindly agreed to lead certain areas of the challenge. You can find out more about them by visiting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/about/&quot;&gt;about page&lt;/a&gt; (please do, they really are awesome people). With their help I was able to flesh out what the challenge would look like and how it might work.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Then it came to starting to talk about the challenge more openly. This was the point of no return and I to be completely honest I was pretty nervous about it! However, not only was the news of the challenge greeted with lots of enthusiasm, the response to my plea for help with accommodation was truly heart-warming. People who I hadn’t seen in a long time took the time to message and offer their support. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have even been lucky enough to get some sponsors. Having the backing of Mizuno for my shoes and The Active Injury Clinic for my physio is a massive boost for me. A friend has offered to help with Strength &amp;amp; Conditioning and a family friend has said he will sort out a car for the support team to travel in. There is even more exciting news on the horizon with another sponsor all but confirmed. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you to all of these people and to everyone who donates. Your support helps motivate me to get out of the door and keep running but much more importantly it will help us to raise lots of money and awareness for the Refugee Council.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/05/11/Early-thank-yous.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/05/11/Early-thank-yous.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am Running for Refugees</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like a challenge. This summer, I’ll be running 32 marathons in 36 days, covering the 950 miles from the very bottom to the very top of the UK. I’ve never actually run further than 13 miles in a go, so the prospect of pegging it all the way from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Land%27s_End_to_John_o%27_Groats&quot;&gt;Land’s End to John O’Groats&lt;/a&gt; on foot is more than a little terrifying.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Why am I doing this? That’s the easy bit. I want to raise money and awareness for the amazing work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.refugeecouncil.org.uk/&quot;&gt;The Refugee Council&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve all heard a lot this past year about the on-going refugee crisis. It is, in terms of the number of people, the largest refugee crisis since WWII. It can be hard, however, to appreciate the individual stories behind these headline statistics and it’s on this individual level that the work of The Refugee Council makes such a difference. For those that have made the treacherous journey just to escape violence and persecution at home, The Refugee Council lends a helping a hand and supports them and their families to start a new life.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Aside from training, I’ll spend the time between now and when I do the run in September learning about the work of The Refugee Council, understanding what they do and how it makes a difference. I’ll share what I’ve learned both on this blog and via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlXODHddYr5kSIObUM3VHA?nohtml5=False&quot;&gt;my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Follow this blog, share the project with people you know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/runningforrefugees/photos/a.1009557112452059.1073741828.944238958983875/1009556542452116/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot;&gt;become a host location en-route&lt;/a&gt; - any support is massively appreciated. You can also directly support our fundraising efforts by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/mattisrunningforrefugees/&quot;&gt;donating here&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Matt G.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 10:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/03/05/I-am-Running-for-Refugees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.runningforrefugees.co.uk/2016/03/05/I-am-Running-for-Refugees.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
